CURRICULUM VITAE

ASHEESH KUMAR.

E-mail: asheeshsharma17@gmail.com

Phone: 7898154018

Address for Correspondence:

135,ward 12 Lahar road Mihona near kanchan house Dist-Bhind (M.P)

Career Objective:-

To utilize my core technical competency and act as a solution finder for individual and organizational goals.

Educational Qualification:-

Sr. No.	Qualification	Percentage	Year of Passing	University/Board
1.	B.E (Electronics & Instrumentation Engineering)	61.10%	2012-2016	Samrat Ashok Technological Institute, Vidisha (M.P.) (Govt engg college
2.	HSSC.	70%	2011	Agrawal VidhyaMandir , Bhind(M.P.)
3.	S.S.C.	74.3%	2009	Agrawal VidhyaMandir , Bhind(M.P.).)

INTERNSHIP:-

Organization- Centre for Research & Industrial Staff Performance (Indo-German Technical Cooperation), Bhopal(M.P.) / 4 weeks

Accomplishments-In Organization During these Four weeks, I have learned how to control and operate sensors and limit switches

Professional Experience:-

Automation Engineer (February to present)

Lineomatic Graphic industries Ahmedabad (Machine manufacturers)

➤ Automation Engineer (November 2019 to Feb 2020)

Pima control pvt. Ltd Ahmedabad System House of rockwell automation.

➤ Project Engineer (Aug 2017 to 05 November 2019)

Nish techno project pvt ltd Surat System house of schneider electric ➤ Field Service Engineer trainee (JUNE 2016 to FEB 2017)

E spectrum medical solutions pvt ltd Delhi

Roles and Responsibilities:-

- ➤ I/O testing of plc panel & worked on maximum 30000 I/O in single project
- Installation of all type of field instruments like Flow meter, level transmitter, pressure transmitter, RTD and all other instruments.
- Calibration of flow meter ,pressure transmitter & level transmitter
- ➤ Having experience in FBD ,Ladder logic & ST programming.
- ➤ Loop testing of all type of instruments ,Actuator & Feeders
- Commissioning of all instruments .
- Have good hands on communication using modbus, serial or plc
- > interfacing with Gsv modem & GSM modem.
- Preparation of FAT report.
- Preparation of SAT report
- SCADA development and Scada programming.
- > PLC programming.
- Schneider M340,M580,Fuji Plc
- > HMI programming.
- > Vijeo citect Scada development & report generation.
- > Preparation of progress claim certificate
- 6.6 kv ,11 kv switchyard panel testing

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES:-

- Was a member of college cricket team in B.E. 1st year
- Organized basic electronics & arduino workshops in college.
- Was Co-Convener in Student activity committee (SAC) in Samrat Utsav 2015.
- Contributed actively in organizing teacher's day in our department.
- Actively contributed in organizing various events at school and college.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:-

- PLC (Programmable Logic Controllers) & DCS (Distributed Control System) -Programming languages such as LD(Ladder Diagram) & FBD (Functional Block Diagram)
- Hands on Practical exposure in brands as Schneider, Fuji
- SCADA (Supervisory Control & Data Acquisition) Screen designing, PC & PLC interface, Data collection & storage
- HMI (Human Machine Interface) Screen designing, PLC interface, DCS interface
- Sizing & Selection of Pneumatics & Field Instruments (Control Valve, Sensors, Level

- Transmitters, Flow Transmitters, Temperature Transmitters, Pressure Switches)
- Interfacing between PLC & Scada using various type of communication.
- Knowledge in PID(Proportional Integral Derivative)
- Troubleshooting Control Panel (Power wiring & Control wiring)
- Commissioning & Troubleshooting sensors , limit switch, flow meters, level transmitters, pressure transmitters
- Electrical measurement and process Instrumentation
- Fundamental of Instrumentation
- PLC programming

Academic Projects:-

- Major project- Automatic irrigation system.
- Minor project- Clap controlled switch

SOFTWARE:-

Unity pro, Vijeo designer, Vijeo citect MS Word, PowerPoint, RSLOGIX 500

LANGUAGES:-

Ladder logic, function block diagram

Personal Profile:-

Name : Asheesh Kumar Father's Name: . Mr.Santosh Kumar Birth Date : 08th august, 1993

Age : 26 year Gender : Male Nationality : Indian

Languages Known : English, Hindi ,Gujrati

HOBBIES : Listening Music and playing, Playing cricket

I hereby declare that details furnished above are true to the best of my knowledge.

Yours Faithfully

(Asheesh Kumar)